<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog of Random things</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Blog of Random things</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 10:11:01 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Diablo2 Resurrected 23月记录</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-2022-03-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 10:11:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-2022-03-19/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-2022-03-19/ -&lt;p>2022二三月的Diablo2是2.3.1的版本的末期，现在网上的消息都是2.4PTR的各种buff，和对天梯的展望。在这个版本末期物价相对比较低的时候，我也算pay to win了一把，在ebay上买了无限，悔恨和信心，这对游戏体验有了很大的提高。玩游戏这么多年头一次体验钞能力，真的很香。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>无限是这三个符文之语中第一个买的，既是最贵的，也是最实用的。有了无限，原来的纯冰法转成了电法，这样MF和刷钥匙体验好很多。由于集中刷钥匙，装备方面解放了很多专门MF的，替给了死灵，这样一直闲置的死灵反而焕发了第二春成了MF的主力。死灵打了几把Baal，刷出了漆甲，法师换上了塔拉夏全套，一方面终于不愁抗性，另外一方面所有的MF装备都交给了死灵，让死灵MF更高。另外这个无限的roll还是很不错的，前几个月的话，这么一个可以换一把差点的无限和很多东西吧。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>悔恨其实并不是那么需要，钥匙凑得差不多的时候，我的双热圣骑已经转成了盾丁，所以对主手需求已经不大了。买悔恨一是不贵，二是有了悔恨即使是盾丁，平时双热战斗力也不错。还有一个就是有了悔恨，打出#28的话就可以不用纠结搞刚毅了，虽然到现在也没看到#28号的影子，脸比较黑吧。6boss算是圣骑的毕业典礼吧，总是感觉自己的血太少，搜刮一下所有的账号，把能用的小符都用上了。6boss的流程有惊无险，最难的其实还是莉莉丝，主要是高塔的图不好找，太黑了。圣骑现在坐等第二套钥匙，不过现在才打了6把，钥匙的掉率还是挺坑的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/red-door.gif" alt="red-door">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>火炬出了亚马逊的，正好开一个弓马，选择了物理弓这个很吃装备的练法。因为已经有了大炮，所以噩梦难度都很安逸。但是因为血加了太少，第三幕老莫前面还是有点痛苦的，娃娃太猛了。因为自己攻击力不够，贫血的问题在地狱更加明显，这就让我买了信心。信心这个武器真是bug，有了它，弓马通地狱一点压力都没有了。弓马练完以后，就看到了2.4PTR的Buff，想想前面的投掷野蛮人，这两个职业是练早了，不过也更能体会Buff的必要。物理弓最大的问题就是攻击没有技能加成，完全看武器，而堆命中的话，血又是问题，不好平衡。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>弓马通关以后，专门刷牛场，我这个装备下的物理弓在牛场效率太低，还不如当初的春饼，所以转成了标枪。标枪还是很爽的，配装因为不需要MF，所以其实还是比较自由。抗性板子都给了圣骑，自己抗性太低，遇到电免的副手用信心打，一级魔法箭，4点多重箭就够用了，足见信心的OP。从通关的角度亚马逊好像还是元素弓更合适，不过自己没体验过。2.4PTR女族长可以给佣兵用了，未来我这把信心用处会更大吧。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>后面又练了两个职业，一个陷阱刺客，一个双球法师。这两个职业都算是开荒比较好的选择。在有遗产的情况下，我还是觉得陷阱刺客比较安逸。一是有能量消解，跑路很快，算是弥补了没有传送的不足，而且法师在升级的过程中其实传送特不是很流畅，一方面高速施法还没堆起来，另一方面耗魔续航也是问题。二是有心灵震爆这个控场神技，可以有效的控制自己受到的伤害，这个要比法师安全多了。陷阱刺客的另外一个优势就是在有眼光的加持下，魔的消耗基本没有。不像双球法师，大火球在有眼光的时候，有时候魔还不够用，特别是40多级技能等级和高速施法上来以后。流程方面，陷阱刺客用纯火焰陷阱通噩梦，然后地狱第一张打完女伯爵转电系，整体流程很顺滑，也可能是遗产还算充沛的原因吧。法师我练的是主火的，一直处于缺魔的状态，升级路上应该加点能量的。地狱第一章开始很艰难，我那时才55级左右，技能点还不够支撑双系，跳过了很多任务快速打到第三章崔凡克，这时等级也上来了，再回来清任务就好很多了。目前这个法师常驻刷安姐，争取能出个乔丹之石吧，其实大军，马拉，旭日东升我也都没有。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>中间还玩了一阵子野蛮狼，这个build的确挺奇葩的，虽然攻击力不强，但是自己和小弟都是血牛，很安逸，即使在MF装的情况下刷起Baal也没啥生存压力，不像死灵，碰到电鬼还是很想换图。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>最后总结一下最近MF的收获：漆甲，虫链，丧钟，雷森得，乌鸦之霜和蚀肉骑士。符文方面一个贝。符文之语方面自己做了一个橡树之心，誓约和执法者。现在其实比起MF搞装备，对练级兴趣更大，研究一个职业在什么等级用什么技能装备搭配，还有就是各种build。而且build这方面不是成型以后刷出了试试，很多时候是练起来才更有意思，当然除了野蛮狼这类需要等级到了才能用的。我想这也是暗黑赛季的魅力吧。&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-2022-03-19/ -</description></item><item><title>Diablo2 Resurrected 野蛮人</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-throwing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 17:00:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-throwing/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-throwing/ -&lt;p>去年10月底开始练野蛮人，年底没机会玩，今天1月又非常忙，陆陆续续几个月，到了这个周末才把野蛮人通关：&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/throwingEndGame.gif" alt="throwing">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>以前其实野蛮人玩得不多，那时候一是觉得野蛮人没啥攻击效率，比起法系的差太多。二是觉得野蛮人的武器专精技能很郁闷，那时没有洗点，加哪个专精感觉都很亏。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>这次想练野蛮人其实是因为打到了狼嚎头盔，当时正在玩狼德，对狼的玩法感觉很爽，就想体验一下野蛮狼这个比较奇葩的玩法。狼嚎这个装备要79级才能用，一路练上来选择了投掷这个也是相对比较冷门的玩法。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>投掷这种练法的核心其实就是武器和钱。武器方面战争之鸟啥的当然是没有，打出了3把70级可以用的飞斧，感觉够用了，就开始练了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>普通难度没啥问题，有西钢全套的遗产，还有天使套，督瑞尔啥的都是基本装备碾压过去。第三幕开始使用投掷武器，低等级武器基本都是赌博里面搞个黄金就能用了。30级进入噩梦，压力也不大，44级拿起来四把死亡碎片，还是很爽的，算是野蛮人的强势期。在噩梦后期，由于没有再好的装备，其实效率就有点低了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>59级通了噩梦，我比较头铁的进了地狱，在第一章基本上被小兵虐。只能回到噩梦练到了68级，拿起恶魔之供，才又进了地狱。60级的这段空挡还是比较郁闷的，没有前面玩的几个职业顺滑。我是刷了几次巴尔，不过升级真是挺快的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>混到70级拿起飞斧，在地狱才比较好混下去：&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/knife.gif" alt="knife">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>投掷野蛮人相比其他物理系职业的一大优势就是这个武器上自带了全系的属性攻击，这样对付物免的怪物非常方便，不用特意考虑破物免的手段，处理物免怪的打击效率也不低。而且这把武器240的数量，在现在的版本续航也不是太成问题。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>地狱第二幕第三幕都比较顺利。到第四幕超市，感觉米山强度很不够，经常死。这个时候的米山也不便宜了，除了修武器，复活也是一大笔开销。不过这个是自己配装的问题，用的眼光给自己提供回蓝，没有足够的吸血。打完diablo，从德鲁伊那里拿了丧钟过来，米山的生存能力强了不少。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>通了巴尔也才到79级，最后也就没转狼，用投掷玩法通关了，通关装备如下：&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/throwing.gif" alt="throwing">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>两把飞斧，亚瑞特头，督瑞尔的壳，不朽之王三件套，矮人，吸血戒指，和新月项链。带新月比较鸡肋，是个没办法的选择。一方面没有大军啥的，虫链因为不用破物免所以没啥用处。米山因为换了丧钟，所以野蛮人自己需要吸魔，所以最后就选了新月，来保证魔法。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>投掷这个玩法，需要足够的遗产，钞能力也很重要，地狱打下来花了100万左右，单看这个人物肯定是入不敷出的，不过暗黑2里钱还是挺好搞的。好的武器是很重要的，而且一把是不够的，两把最少，4把最好。要是无形回复数量的也是得凑成一对才能用。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>通关留念。&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2-throwing/ -</description></item><item><title>Jan 2022 Stock Market</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/trading/2022-01-spy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/trading/2022-01-spy/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/trading/2022-01-spy/ -&lt;p>January 2022 was not a good month for stock market. The market was down and a lot of sellings going on. Looking at SPY ETF prices from Nov 2021 to Jan 2022 (All prices are from Yahoo Finance):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/2022-jan-spy/SPY.png" alt="SPY-JAN-2022">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not only the prices went down, it has gone down below 20 day SMA, 50 day SMA, 100 day SMA and 200 day SMA very quickly within a few days. 200 day SMA is particularly important support level as it is usually used separate bull and bear market. This is particularly worrying if we looked back last 3 months, when prices only tested 100 day SMA and it gave quite good support. Luckily with last two trading days pushes, SPY was able to push above 200 day SMA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking at aggregated price changes at week to date (WTD), month to date (MTD) level:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/2022-jan-spy/Percentage.png" alt="Percentage-JAN-2022">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>January almost went down 10% towards the end of the month. The month would ended quite ugly if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the big push ups on 28th and 31st. The month ended with about 6% down which is not that bad comparing to Dec when the market went up a little less than 6%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would now be the time to take profit or stop loss? Or it is a time to get into the market for a bargain price?&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/trading/2022-01-spy/ -</description></item><item><title>一个开始与一个结束</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/dune-007/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 19:37:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/dune-007/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/dune-007/ -&lt;p>2019年到了香港以后我还没看过电影，一是赶上香港多事，二是自己觉得电影票挺贵的。其实倒不是负担不起，主要是以前有单位员工优惠，看定影太便宜了，没有比较就没有伤害。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>其实在香港看电影还是挺方便的，从家步行就可以到电影院，这样看晚场也不会很麻烦。九十月份终于看了两部电影，一部是沙丘，一部是新007。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/dune/dune_flyer.gif" alt="dune">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>沙丘没有在首映去，是在中秋晚上看的。香港上映时间还是挺早的，不是全球最早，但是比英美早了不少。Dune这个名字其实还是久仰的，小时候虽然没玩过Dune2（我是命令与征服才开始玩电脑游戏的），但是还很记得Dune2000出来的时候四处买盗版盘的场景。小说的剧情有所耳闻，其实自己也没看过，只知道是个很牛的系列。这么说来，自己也就是个路人粉吧，最期待的可能是汉斯季默的音乐。看电影之前，我已经看了大聪的预热，还算是很期待吧。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/dune/dune.gif" alt="dune-ticket">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>电影给我的感觉是有点慢，开始姐妹会的剧情其实对于路人还是有点满头问号的。不过主角一行到了Dune后，整体节奏还是不错的。虽然一开始就知道这不是一个完整的故事，但是当到结束看到It is just the beginning的时候还是有点小失望的。在我的记忆中，一个电影还是应该是一个完整的故事，未完待续不应该在电影中出现。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>对于沙丘这个体量的故事，分两部是可以理解的。这些年长故事分两部也不是沙丘第一次搞。但是如果比较一下漫威，虽然复仇者联盟最后分成了两部，但是第一步的高潮还是满足的。沙丘只是一个故事的节点来结束，但是我觉得这个结束的地方情绪并不高潮。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>插句题外话，最近补了正义联盟导剪版，都是华纳的，如果当初扎导可以把正义联盟剪成两部，也就没有后面这么多一地鸡毛了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>说回到沙丘，我觉得一个很好的比较对象是银翼杀手2049。2049虽然节奏也很慢，但是一部片子讲了一个完整的故事，很多的设定并没有在电影里讲，二是用动画短片的形式在电影之前补了，这种模式其实我觉得更好。沙丘的世界更宏大，电影里其实对宇航工会，香料，姐妹会啥的都没怎么具体解释，宇航工会都没提到。这些设定如果可以通过类似的方式在上映前就预热，效果会很好吧。但是商业上会有多大的不同我就不懂了。总结一下，沙丘整体观影过程我觉得还不错，大场面的制作还是很能值回票价的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>去看沙丘的另外一个原因就是这可能是自己真正可以经历的一个科幻巨制吧。星球大战我只算是经历了后传3部曲，前面六部都不是自己时代的东西。黑客帝国虽然最后一部是在电影院看的，但是第一部我还是多年之后补的。指环王自己到现在还没看过。希望沙丘这次可以打破魔咒，成为一个成功的系列电影，这样我也可以亲历一下。电影我只刷了一次，支持一张CD吧，也算是为未来的经典做贡献。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>沙丘是一个美丽的开始，那新的007就是一个完美结局。我是看着布鲁斯南007长大的，对丹尼尔先天是排斥的。布鲁斯南版在脑中的印象总是很炫的科技，有点更未来的意味。而丹尼尔版给我的感觉总是更贴近生活。当然，很重要的原因是自己前些年都在伦敦生活，并且像天幕危机中的有些场景，是自己每天上班路上都会走过的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/dune/007_flyer.gif" alt="007">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>去看新007前其实没做什么功课，对上一集基本上没啥印象了，所以其实故事上看的是有点蒙的。但是整体展开还是不错的，故事可以说是高潮迭起，其实没看上一部把这部当一个故事也还是能看的。不过如果有两部连演，会是个很好的体验。不过这种模式会是票房毒药吧，因为长度的原因，翻场太少。不过票要是贵上一点是不是可以呢？不知道有没有电影院实践过这个模式。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>整体看完这部007，非常感动，一方面故事本身在007里就是很煽情的一作，更重要的是感动一个离开的演员可以有这么完满的银幕结局。当然这种设计也是有商业利益的考虑，情怀毕竟是需要买单的，但是在买单之余，我更能感到一种尊重，这也是最让我感动的。丹尼尔，与天幕危机里面的M，洛根里的狼叔，甚至终局之战中的Tony，都通过同一种方式让我知道离别的时候也是可以有尊重和掌声的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/dune/007.gif" alt="007-ticket">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>最后说说电影院的观影体验。沙丘是一部很适合电影院的电影，在小屏幕上看的话会感觉很浪费这么宏大的宇宙尺度的场面。007的话，电影院的音响效果带来了更好的沉浸式体验和感动。所以两部电影还是很适合电影院看的。两部电影我都选了当天的最后一场，因为疫情的原因，全程需要戴口罩，这个没啥，就是不能吃爆米花和喝可乐有点遗憾吧。两部电影都是快晚上12点才结束，这带来了一个始料不及的不友好，因为看完电影的心情，影响了入睡，两个晚上我都是两点多才睡的。以后还是看早场的吧。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>愿丹尼尔一路走好，愿沙丘系列成为一代经典。&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/dune-007/ -</description></item><item><title>Diablo2 Resurrected 游戏体验</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:53:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2/ -&lt;p>暗黑破坏神2九月23号上市了，第一时间入手，一方面是最近的确有点时间玩，另一方面也是怀旧一下。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>其实我这个怀旧还和很多人不太一样。Diablo2原版小的时候一定是玩过的，但是其实印象也不是很深刻，只记得第二幕的督瑞尔很难搞，当时好像玩了个圣骑，荆棘感觉很强，其他的就记不得什么了。后来在上大学的时候和朋友联机1.09倒是玩的挺欢乐，前一阵子倒腾老硬盘，还找到了当时的存档，冰封球法师，很有1.09的时代感。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>我的怀旧怀的倒是9年前的3代，3代刚发售的时候正好赶上我在搞论文，那时候压力真的是满大的，白天搞论文，晚上就Diablo3消遣，话说当时Error 37也看了不少，不过感觉没有这次服务器的问题郁闷，也许是年头多了，这些不好的也就忘了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>说回2代重置，这次起手开荒是召唤死灵。召唤死灵对装备要求真的是低，号称一条腰带就可以通地狱不是浪得虚名。而且召唤死灵的整个通关流程是非常顺滑的，30级进噩梦，60级进地狱也不会感到难度陡增。就是当时不知道传送杖为何物，打地狱虫洞的确有些郁闷，慢的要死。要说唯一的难度，应该就是普通的督瑞尔了吧。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>随着玩死灵，我也在网上看看各种build的介绍和刷装备的教程，老游戏的优势就是可以抄作业，照着别人的搞就好了。也许少了游戏的乐趣，但是我玩游戏有时就是不想动脑子，杀时间放松，所以抄作业也挺好。28号通了死灵，第一幕的地穴刷了几次，没出啥好东西，就开始下一个人物了。死灵的遗产主要是一些好搞的符文之语，像是眼光，知识，烟雾，隐秘啥的，这些通关的过程中做起来，对流程还是帮助挺大的。现在死灵上的不多，有时候KP一下，装备很垃圾，都堆了MF，抗性啥惨目忍睹。主手精神剑加精神盾，运气守护，黄金包袱，头和护身符都是+1技能的黄金装，两个拿各戒指。MF堆到了283%。副手用骷髅收集者双手杖，把MF堆到了367%。装备都是其实大多都是后来从法师那里继承的，自己打出来的不多。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/nec-off.png" alt="nec-off">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>第二个练的是法师，冰火法，主修暴风雪，噩梦后期开始辅修的火球。普通和噩梦都没啥难度，一开始续航比较差，没有回蓝。27级佣兵拿起眼光，问题就解决了。60级刚一进地狱压力蛮大，主要是技能点少，火球攻击力还不行，而第一个地穴任务冰免的怪还不少，佣兵也扛不住，打得挺郁闷的。回到噩梦KM一阵子，65级再开始地狱情况就好多了，同时装备也有提升不少。不过打到地狱第5幕还是挺有点难度的，进入冰河就直接被电鬼秒了。刷了几次地图，在一个相对好的配置下总算通关了。3BB其实也不是很好打，把身上的药都用了，才打过去。通关以后重置成了纯冰，开始MF之路。刚开始KM都比较费劲，主要打安姐，随着装备提升慢慢开始KM和KP。纯冰的法师虽然暴风雪攻击高，但是感觉第四幕和第五幕都刷不了。好在KM足以养家了，暗金的日用品一般通关就够用了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/sor-main.png" alt="sor-main">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>现在法师的装备眼球，军帽，副手精神盾，运气守护，站旅啥的都有了，标准的MF配置。戒指护身符啥的好的一个没打出来不过，现在用的还是+3冰技能的护身符。马拉，乔丹之石，大君啥的都还没见过，这个比较残念。副手用的是海鸥MF可以堆到478%。刷牛场的话衣服换上奥马斯，手套换上法师之拳，暴风雪在5K的伤害，感觉还行吧。和高玩比不了，但是自己娱乐也够用了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>下面练了一个圣骑士，双热配置，这是唯一一个不缺抗性的，但是武器比较垃圾，所以打怪真的慢。平常偶尔打打庇护所，但是MF太低，只能算是练级了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/pal.png" alt="pal">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>法师打出了棍子，所以接下来练了一个狼德。这个狼德属于装备都有的情况下才开始练的，所以整个通关流程都挺顺利的。粉碎者31级就能拿起来，这让噩梦的流程非常舒适，升级后攻击力也很猛。狼德这种玩法也很热血，因为野性狂暴的时间，一打起来就会比较上头，游玩体验比较流畅和爽快。这个build也属于成型比较早的，比较适合走流程的玩法。不过因为用了双手武器，少了盾牌这个可以提供抗性的大户，感觉抗性真的不好堆，最后没办法，穿了背信靠影散来堆。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/diablo2/dur.png" alt="dur">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>下面一段时间玩不了游戏了，暗黑倒不是像RPG，放下了就很难再拿起来。计划是把剩下的3个职业都通了吧，野蛮人准备练个投掷的，亚马逊自然是练个弓马，刺客练个陷阱的吧，容易一点。暗金装备准备了七七八八，风之力这种残念物自然是没有，但是通关日用品应该算是差不多了。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>其他的build，无限电法和野蛮狼有点兴趣搞一下。不过无限也是一个怨念物，野蛮狼的头盔倒是有了，不过这个69级才能用，所以要用其他build练起来然后洗点。还有就是火狼，但是锤子还没刷到。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>至于符文之语，这个就只能随缘了。干了这么久其实高符一共没打到几个，感觉这个坑比暗金装备大不少。最想弄得可能就是一个无限，这样可以搞个电法。现在可以想的是橡树之心和誓约，#26和#23已经有了，需要两个#21。#21虽然有的用了，但是感觉不是那么怨念的东西。还有就是希望打到几个好的暗金戒指和护身符，这样抗性不会这么拉跨。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>作为一个20年的老游戏，总体来说这段时间的体验还是不错的。几周前的服务器问题的确是比较郁闷，现在排队虽然也烦，但是好歹进去了就不会被踢出来，所以进游戏就别退出就好。总体来说值回票价。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>希望暴雪的改进就是把天梯的人物数量提高，20个其实在考虑所有build的情况下的确是有点少，再说谁没有几个存东西的小号呢？或者把箱子改成无限的吧。&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/diablo2/ -</description></item><item><title>[抄作业] MASA的味噌拌炒豬肉茄子</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/japanese-eggplant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 13:06:25 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/japanese-eggplant/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/japanese-eggplant/ -&lt;p>看了MASA的&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ucEXNoVQdm0&amp;amp;ab_channel=MASA%E3%81%AE%E6%96%99%E7%90%86ABC">味噌拌炒豬肉茄子定食&lt;/a>，今天照着做了一个：&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/foods/eggplant.jpg" alt="eggplant">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>没买红椒，所以就略过了，少了一个颜色，但是加了红葱头。加了豆腐干，上周剩的，不要浪费。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>几个可以提高的地方：&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>我的料比较多，所以汁调少了，整个菜看着有点干&lt;/li>
&lt;li>加了老抽，颜色有点深，可以不放&lt;/li>
&lt;li>买的切好的肉，有点厚，不是很入味&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>总体还是挺好吃的！MASA的菜谱还是很推荐的。&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/japanese-eggplant/ -</description></item><item><title>How fast can I read?</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/softwares/disk-read/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 15:04:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/softwares/disk-read/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/softwares/disk-read/ -&lt;p>Computer storage has changed so much over last few decades, in both size and speed terms. We see a lot of amazing performance test results for NVMe drives nowadays. We could copy files much faster from one place to another. But what does it mean for software developers? How fast we shall expect our code to read? The following is some test results I have done in Java.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The data file I am trying to read is the &lt;a href="https://www.gdeltproject.org/data.html#rawdatafiles">GDELT 1.0 Event database&lt;/a>. The file name is: GDELT.MASTERREDUCEDV2.1979-2013.zip, which is 1.01 GB in zip format and 6.12 GB when uncompressed. The reason I picked this file is because it is real data and at the same time big enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="old-results">Old Results&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I firstly ran the test with my old desktop in Feb, which has Intel i5 6400 CPU and a SanDisk SSD Plus 1T drive. The drive is using SATA 3. The code is quite simple:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">LargeFileReadingTest&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">static&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">void&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">main&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">final&lt;/span> String&lt;span style="color:#f92672">[]&lt;/span> args&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">throws&lt;/span> Exception &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">long&lt;/span> start &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> System&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">currentTimeMillis&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">();&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">int&lt;/span> lineCount &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> 0&lt;span style="color:#f92672">;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> ZipFile zipFile &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> ZipFile&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;C:\\Codes\\temp\\io\\GDELT.MASTERREDUCEDV2.1979-2013.zip&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">);&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">try&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>BufferedReader reader &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> BufferedReader&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> InputStreamReader&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>zipFile&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">getInputStream&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>zipFile&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">entries&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">().&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">nextElement&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">()))))&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">while&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>reader&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">readLine&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">()&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">!=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">null&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> lineCount&lt;span style="color:#f92672">++;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">long&lt;/span> duration &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> System&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">currentTimeMillis&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">()&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span> start&lt;span style="color:#f92672">;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e">// Expected to be: 87298047
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">assert&lt;/span> lineCount &lt;span style="color:#f92672">==&lt;/span> 87298047&lt;span style="color:#f92672">;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> System&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">out&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">println&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Duration &amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span> duration&lt;span style="color:#f92672">);&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>When I read the file from zip, it takes 32.326 secs to finish. When I read unzipped file using a BufferedReader with default buffer size (which is 8192), it takes 24.473 secs. When I increase the buffer size to 4096 * 512, it takes 28.618 secs. If I reduce the buffer size to 1024, it takes 22.136 secs. Reading unzipped file directly is about 260 MB/s given the file size, while SATA 3 has a read speed up to 545 MB/s based on &lt;a href="https://shop.westerndigital.com/en-ap/products/internal-drives/sandisk-ssd-plus-sata-iii-ssd#SDSSDA-120G-G27">data sheet from SanDisk&lt;/a>. These test results are based on one off runs, which may not that accurate. But since I already &lt;a href="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/old-machine">pulled the desktop apart&lt;/a>, I cannot really rerun the tests unfortunately. I was hoping to get faster read by reading the zipped file but I suspect it didn&amp;rsquo;t work because my CPU (i5 6400) is not that fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="testing-with-nvme">Testing with NVMe&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that I have new machines I can rerun the tests. I have done three more tests, one with a Lenovo M920q with Intel i7-9700T and Samsung 970 EVO NVMe, another with a NUC11 with Intel i7-1165G7 and Samsung SSD 970 EVO Plus NVMe, and lastly with the same NUC but a different drive, which is WD Black SN750 NVMe. This time I tried to be more accurate. For each test, I run 10 times, instead of just once. The tests are done on Windows 10 version 10.0.19042 and Java version is 14.0.2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The testing result is as follows. All times are in milliseconds:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Reading Zip&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">DefaultBufferSize&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">1024BufferSize&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">4096Times512BufferSize&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">M920&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">24894.5 ± 351.7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">12325.9 ± 460.6&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">15345.6 ± 537.0&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">14294.3 ± 148.5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">NUC with Samsung disk&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">18861.6 ± 449.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">8928.9 ± 256.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">10414.3 ± 373.8&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">10569.4 ± 125.6&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">NUC with WD Black&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">18878.2 ± 311.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">8666.2 ± 267.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">10289.6 ± 401.5&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">10206.0 ± 189.9&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h4 id="reading-zip">Reading Zip&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Looking at &lt;code>Reading Zip&lt;/code> speed, both M920q and NUC11 are slower than &lt;code>DefaultBufferSize&lt;/code> case, where unzipped file is read. The faster read with &lt;code>DefaultBufferSize&lt;/code> suggests that the bottleneck when &lt;code>Reading Zip&lt;/code> is on CPU rather than disk IO. Since the code is single threaded, the performance differences are linked to the single core max turbo frequency:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">CPU&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Max Turbo Frequency&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Reading Zip Performance&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Old Desktop&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">i5 6400&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/sku/88185/intel-core-i56400-processor-6m-cache-up-to-3-30-ghz/specifications.html">3.30 GHz&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">32326&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">M920&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">i7 9700T&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/sku/191048/intel-core-i79700t-processor-12m-cache-up-to-4-30-ghz/specifications.html">4.30 GHz&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">24894.5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">NUC&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">i7 1165G7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/sku/208662/intel-core-i71165g7-processor-12m-cache-up-to-4-70-ghz/specifications.html">4.70 GHz&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">18869.9&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Trying to fit these 3 data points linearly:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/disk-read/zip_speed.png" alt="zip">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using this simple fitted model, naively, to achieve the same speed as &lt;code>DefaultBufferSize&lt;/code> on M920, I would need a CPU with max turbo speed of 5.52 GHz. For NUC, I would need a CPU with max turbo speed of 5.90 GHz. I am not experienced in overclocking and not sure if they are practical or not. But it feels like trading CPU for disk IO on local disk setup doesn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="defaultbuffersize">DefaultBufferSize&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Looking at &lt;code>DefaultBufferSize&lt;/code> value by itself, it is interesting to see that NUC is about 28% faster compared to M920 while the drive has comparable sequential read performance:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">SSD&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Data Sheet Sequential Read&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Observed Read Performance&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Samsung SSD 970 EVO&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;a href="https://www.samsung.com/semiconductor/minisite/ssd/product/consumer/970evo/">Up to 3,400 MB/s&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">519.23 MB/s&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Samsung SSD 970 EVO Plus&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;a href="https://www.samsung.com/semiconductor/minisite/ssd/product/consumer/970evoplus/">Up to 3,500 MB/s&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">716.77 MB/s&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">WD Black SN750&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;a href="https://shop.westerndigital.com/products/internal-drives/wd-black-sn750-nvme-ssd#WDS250G3X0C">up to 3,400 MB/s&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">738.50 MB/s&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Without any hard evidence, I suspect M920 is slower because I use it as a server and there are 4 VMs it is running. The 970 EVO is the only drive which runs OS and everything else. Something else is slowing down it. This is partially supported by the fact that NUC running 970 EVO Plus is slightly slower than WD Black because the WD drive is the secondary drive while 970 EVO Plus runs the OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps a more important question to ask is can I read faster? Naively, I tired to run multiple reads in different threads. If the bottleneck is disk in single thread scenario, the read speed per thread shall be slowed down proportional to the number of threads. Testing on M920 with 2 threads, the average time to read with &lt;code>DefaultBufferSize&lt;/code> is 13436.2 milliseconds. This gives 952 MB/s. So, it is not the disk which is the bottleneck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then is it the java code (&lt;code>BufferedReader&lt;/code> and &lt;code>InputStreamReader&lt;/code>) which is less optimal? Some Googling leads me to &lt;a href="https://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com/2011/12/java-sequential-io-performance.html">Martin&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a>, which is quite interesting. However, I will let my SSD to have some rest and give this a spin in another day.&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/softwares/disk-read/ -</description></item><item><title>My Desk Setup July 2021</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/desk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:08:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/desk/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/desk/ -&lt;p>Working from home is becoming a norm due to COVID. Not surprisingly, proper home office setup is becoming trendy. I have watched a lot of videos on Youtube regarding desk setup. It feels like I shall write down my setup as well, for future reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because I am renting in HongKong in a fully furnished flat, there is very little I can do about the desk without negotiating with my landlord. So, I kept the desk as it is and try to fit everything into it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/desk.jpg" alt="desk">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My current setup has three screens:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/computing/monitors/led/samsung-27-curved-led-monitor-ls27d590cs-za/">27inch Sumsung HD monitor&lt;/a> I bought in 2016. It is used as my main monitor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dell.com/hr/business/p/dell-u2518d-monitor/pd">Dell 2518D&lt;/a> I bought in 2019 paid by my employer for COVID home office setup. It is set to vertical on the right&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.asus.com/us/Displays-Desktops/Monitors/ZenScreen/ZenScreen-MB16AC/">ASUS Zenscreen MB16AC&lt;/a> I bought in 2018 when I needed to do some coding on the run&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The three monitors are plugged into Intel NUC11 on the left via HDMI, Mini DisplayPort and USB Type-C respectively. The main monitor also connects to a hdmi hub to allow me to use it for PS4 and MyTV Super.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have two keyboards connected. The one below is an &lt;a href="https://ergodox-ez.com/">Ergodox EZ&lt;/a> split keyboard with brown switch. The one on the top is a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-K600-TV-Keyboard-Integrated/dp/B07C6LXYHL/ref=sr_1_1">Logitech K600&lt;/a>. the former is wired and the later is connected via bluetooth. I normally use the Ergodox keyboard but when I connect a second computer (Raspberry Pi or Jetson Nano) to my main monitor, I use the K600 so I don&amp;rsquo;t need to unplug/replug the cables. That is where K600&amp;rsquo;s touchpad helps to reduce the need for an extra mouse. I also use K600 for a little bit of gaming when function keys are required. As my custom layout for Ergodox EZ doesn&amp;rsquo;t have them mapped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For mouse, I have a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Vertical-Wireless-Mouse-Rechargeable/dp/B07FNJB8TT/ref=sr_1_1">Logitech MX vertical&lt;/a> and an &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/hk/shop/product/MJ2R2ZA/A/magic-trackpad-2-silver">Apple Magic Trackpad&lt;/a>. I always enjoyed Mac&amp;rsquo;s trackpad when using my macbook. It is so good to find out that I could use it for Windows with &lt;a href="https://github.com/imbushuo/mac-precision-touchpad">this open source driver&lt;/a>. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t support bluetooth, so one more cable is required, but that is fine for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Webcam-Built-Stereo-Microphones/dp/B01DPNPJ72">Logitech C925&lt;/a> for Zoom and Wechat video. Next to the webcam is a screen bar for lighting. I don&amp;rsquo;t use it that much though. I have an old Creative D200 bluetooth speaker behind the screen which is also connected to the main monitor via cables. This allows my PS4 and MyTV super to output audio as well. When I listen to serious music, like classic music, instead of D200, I use the &lt;a href="https://en.creative.com/p/sound-blaster/sound-blaster-e5">Creative Sound Blaster E5&lt;/a> with my headset, which is &lt;a href="https://www.denon.com/shop/onearheadphone/ahmm400">Denon AH-MM400&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed this 3 screen setup, which is a lot of spaces but also quite compact at the same time. The main monitor is only HD, which is a little bit lacking in today&amp;rsquo;s eye, especially when the vertical monitor is 2K. Having a NUC really helps to reduce the footprint as well compared to a full PC, without much compromise on performance. Although given how hot HongKong is during the summer, I added two fans on each side of the NUC to help reducing the heat, even though the room is usually with AC turned on. I would like a better speaker for music, but given the space left, it is hard to find a good fit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cable management is quite a bit of mess. But I just ignore it for now. I added a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KHRLSTT">16 port USB hub&lt;/a> recently, which helps to reduce the number of cables to NUC, but I shall really spend more time to clean up the cables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a lot of these stuff pre-COVID. The main additions are webcam, vertical monitor and the wireless keyboard. In addition, I have also upgraded my wireless router from a cheap TP link one to ASUS AC68U, so I have faster wifi connection. One thing would really be nice is to have a wired connection from the router in living room to here. But that is too much a change I need to talk to landlord if I want to have the cables in the wall, or too much of a hazard if I just put the cable on the floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Along with the wireless router, there is also a Raspberry Pi 4 connected to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/ORICO-Bay-Hard-Drive-Enclosure/dp/B0734CZSXL/ref=sr_1_6">ORICO 2 bay hard drive enclosure&lt;/a> running plex. As HongKong summer is really hot and living room is usually without AC, I had 2 more fans there to provide extra airflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had more space, I would prefer to have the second monitor horizontal instead of vertical. This is because when I use the main monitor for something else, the vertical monitor doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work as a primary monitor as a lot of applications just don&amp;rsquo;t scale properly or look weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a final note, I think I shall stop buying more stuff as I have more than enough. But &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/desk/ -</description></item><item><title>Meat Day Today!</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/meat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:20:46 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/meat/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/meat/ -&lt;p>It may sound strange but I always found eating out by myself very weird. It maybe due to the fact that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t order many dishes. Maybe it is just the loneness when seating down by myself. Maybe it is because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of things to watch on my phone. I have always prefer to cook myself at home or do takeaways. I even rarely do delivery until early this year during my two weeks&amp;rsquo; quarantine in Hongkong. The last time I eat out by myself this year would go back to my birthday in April, when I went to Outback Steakhouse in Olympian city for lunch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I planed to go Gyu-Kaku for buffet for sometime. It sounds not that good an idea because Gyu-Kaku has always been busy with long queues. Also, I am kind of on diet for past several weeks and I skip dinner completely. But since I am on holiday this week, I feel I shall really go and take advantage of the discount on work day, haha.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did exactly the kind of preparation needed for buffet, skipping dinner last night (as usual) and skipping breakfast this morning as well. So, I went to Gyu-Kaku quite early today at 11:30. Not only because there would be no queue at the time, but also because I am quite hungry at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The no queue experience is good. I chose the US SRF Angus Wagyu Buffet, which is 338 HKD for early bird on work day (90 mins eating). I got my QR code and then ready to order with my phone. Like any software, the website doesn&amp;rsquo;t open. I was cautious about my phone&amp;rsquo;s reception in the restaurant so I took both my phones with me today, both of which don&amp;rsquo;t work on the ordering website. Waiting for 5 mins, I managed to open the page but when submitting the order, the website gave me error connecting to the server. So, I had to get my order done manually with waiter. With another 5 mins waiting, my first round of food finally arrived:
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/meat/first.jpg" alt="first">
The food is nice but it is already 20 mins since I set down!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The website is then up and down from time to time. I got a new QR code from the restaurant. I tired to order second round of food but got different errors. I stopped trying and waited for 5 mins. I did get the food but everything was doubled up since I submitted twice as it failed the first time around (apparently not failed):
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/meat/second.jpg" alt="second">
I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind doubling it up as I enjoyed the food anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, after I got my third QR code, the website is fully functional. I got some more meat:
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/meat/third.jpg" alt="third">
and noodles:
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/meat/noodles.jpg" alt="noodles">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I am eating by myself, I am very much concentrated on eating. So, 90 mins is more than enough to fill me up. I didn&amp;rsquo;t ask for extension of my 90 mins because their technology doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. In the end, I paid 371.8 with 10% service charge. I would argue the service is not that good given all the problems with their website on a grumpy day. But given all the meat I have today after 2 weeks of diet, I am happy enough to just pay and leave.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Foods I enjoyed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The sauce is pretty good to mix with any kind of barbecue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The beef tongues are good for me. It is not a thing I usually cook. So, very nice to have it when I am eating out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enoki mushroom is interesting idea
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/meat/mushroom.jpg" alt="mushroom">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Foods I found a little bit strange:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tripe and intestine are a little bit strange for barbecue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oyster is not as good as I hoped&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After I got home, I opened the website in my phone again as I would like to get a screenshot of all the foods I ordered. Unfortunately, instead of my orders, I got the next customer sitting at my table&amp;rsquo;s order instead. Looking at the webpage URL, there is a token which I guess linked to the QR code, so I guess my QR code just had the wrong expiry. I don&amp;rsquo;t particular mind to see other people&amp;rsquo;s ordering, as it gave me several ideas on what I would like to try next time. But from a software developer perspective, a cross client incident is not good. The QR code should have expired as soon as I paid or it shall still show my orders until some house keeping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The website&amp;rsquo;s URL is: &lt;a href="https://kabu-byod.azurewebsites.net/order?shopCode=GKK-OC&amp;amp;token=">https://kabu-byod.azurewebsites.net/order?shopCode=GKK-OC&amp;amp;token=&lt;/a>. I wonder how much penetration/security tests have been done. It is not something I am familiar with though. So, I won&amp;rsquo;t randomly generate some tokens and try to hit the link.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good lunch with some software failures. My diet continues tomorrow. I am not looking forward to weight myself tomorrow morning though &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/others/meat/ -</description></item><item><title>Salvaging My Old Desktop</title><link>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/old-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 10:09:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/old-machine/</guid><description>Blog of Random things https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/old-machine/ -&lt;p>I have been using a &lt;a href="https://support.hp.com/gb-en/document/c04835128">HP Pavilion 550-153na&lt;/a> desktop for several years. Bought this computer back in 2015 winter as it was on close down sale from Currys. I went in last day after work and it is on 50% off, so I paid 250 pounds and got it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would admit that I bought it more because of the discount rather than the spec. Only when I got home, I really looked into the spec. It has i5-6400 CPU, 8 GB RAM, 2TB hard drive and a Radeon R5 330 graphic card. I have use it over years for writing code and game playing. Game playing is not very good given the spec, but I have to work with what I have and playing less demanding games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been looking at how I could upgrade the machine from time to time. Getting a better graphic card would be an obvious starting point. But, I was worried that the power supply wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good enough and I need to buy another power supply. Power supply is the same reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade the hard drive to SSD, as there is only one SATA power cable. So, I sticked with HDD for years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The machine is far from great but it kind of serves the purpose. So, when I moved from London to HongKong in 2019, I didn&amp;rsquo;t throw it away but carried it over to HongKong. Over the years, the machine has definitely slowed down. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the best way to clean up the hard drive so I installed ubuntu as an alternative operating system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This worked quite well until COVID hits. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to get Citrix working on ubuntu so I had to switch back to Windows so I can remote login to work. I was getting more and more annoyed by the slow spinning disk. In the end, I unplugged the old HDD and bought a 1TB SanDisk SSD Plus. A SSD and a newly installed operating system definitely gave the old machine a second life. As I slowly getting into classic music, the machine&amp;rsquo;s CD drive was also put into use a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coming into 2021 and second year working from home, I desperately wanted a home PC upgrade. I have to admit that there was no particular reason for the upgrade as the old PC still works perfectly fine. Maybe not able to play games was the main pain point. But I knew that was just an excuse. Anyway, I had my eye on the new Intel NUC11 and put in order as soon as it was out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the old PC finally retired. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to throw it away immediately as the parts could be useful somewhere else. The first usage case would be the 2TB hard drive it has. I put it into an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/ORICO-Bay-Hard-Drive-Enclosure/dp/B0734CZSXL/ref=sr_1_6">ORICO 2 bay hard drive enclosure&lt;/a>. This is now connected to my Raspberry Pi and used for downloading and storage for pictures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I took out the CPU and plan to buy a second hand HP 800 G2 mini barebone PC. The SanDisk SSD shall also fit there. I am planning to give this PC to my parents. It shall be powerful enough for their usages for next few years. I also took out the memory from the PC, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know where they could be used for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought this was it and I could now throw the rest of the machine until I bought a Jetson Nano. Jetson Nano doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with wifi. As my routers are in the living room and there is no wired connection to the study room, a wifi is must have if I want to use the Jetson Nano. I searched in old PC box and found that it has a removable Intel 3165 wifi card. So I moved the card and the antenna from the old box into Nano. With some googling, I managed to get the driver working as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been using Nano for several days and didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the fact that I had to unplug/replug the power cable every time I need to start the machine. So I started reading the option of having a power button. It looks quite simple as long as I have a button. Before ordering one from Amazon, I realised that the old PC has the same thing. So this time, I took out the power button and the light and plug it into Nano. Now I can turn on Nano without touching the power supply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to keep the old PC for some more time now given my journey of reusing things. The CPU and hard drive were obvious but the power button was definitely a surprise for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also intriguing to see how little differences in my productivity when using the old machine vs new machine. I measure my productivity crudely by looking at codes I write after work. In 2020, I am writing all of these commits in my old PC:
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/old-machine/2020.PNG" alt="2020">
In 2021, I got the new PC in late Mar:
&lt;img src="https://mcai4gl2.github.io/old-machine/2021.PNG" alt="2021">
In another word, it is very hard to justify the money I spent on buying the new NUC, haha.&lt;/p>
- https://mcai4gl2.github.io/computers/old-machine/ -</description></item></channel></rss>